teachinghistory.org 2018-05-17

# Privacy Policy | Teachinghistory.org

#### Web Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting the Teachinghistory.org website and reviewing our web privacy and security policy and our statistical standards.

Our policy is simple: We collect no personal information about you unless you choose to provide that information to us. We do not give, share, sell, or transfer any personal information to a third party.

#### Links to Other Sites

Teachinghistory.org provides links to many external websites. Please be aware that when you leave the Teachinghistory.org website you will be going to sites that are beyond our control and standards. Websites external to Teachinghistory.org have their own privacy policies, and may collect data or solicit personal information. The privacy and security policies and procedures described for Teachinghistory.org do not apply to any external links. We suggest contacting these sites directly for information on their privacy and security policies. Always be aware of where you end up.

#### Non-personal Information We Record

During your visit as you browse through the website or download information, our operating system will automatically record some general information about your visit.

During your visit, our web operating system will record:

  1. The type of browser (such as “Netscape version X” or “Internet Explorer version X”) that you are using.
  2. The type of operating system that you use (such as Macintosh, Unix, or Windows).
  3. The date and time you visit our site, and the web pages that you visit on our site.
  4. The address of the previous website you were visiting, if you linked to us from another website.
  5. The Internet domain for your Internet service, such as “xcompany.com” or “xcompany.net” if you use a private Internet access account, or "yourschool.edu" if you connect from a college or university domain.

We use this information for statistical analysis, to help us make our site more useful to visitors. This tracking system does not record information about individuals.

#### Web Security Policy

For security purposes and to make sure our website remains available to all users, we use special software programs for monitoring network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise to cause damage to this computer system. These programs collect no information that would directly identify individuals, but they do collect information that could help us identify someone attempting to tamper with this website.

If you use our website, you should understand that all activities may be monitored and recorded. Anyone using this system expressly consents to such monitoring.

WARNING — If such monitoring reveals possible evidence of criminal activity, monitoring records may be provided to law enforcement officials. Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, we make no other attempts to identify individual users or their usage habits. We only use raw monitoring data logs for determining trends in usage patterns and in diagnosing system problems.

#### Information from e-mail you send to us

If you decide to send us an e-mail message, the message will usually contain your return e-mail address. If you include personally-identifying information in your e-mail because you want us to address issues specific to your situation, we may use that information in responding to your request. Also, e-mail is not totally secure against interception. Please send only information necessary to help us process your request.

#### Voluntary Submission of Information

On some of our web pages we provide forms that let you voluntarily submit personal information (such as e-mail address or name). For example, this occurs when you submit a question to one of our experts or when you sign up for our “E-Newsletter” subscription service. In those cases, all submitted information is used only for the expressed purposes for which it is intended and is not made available to any third party.
